Guide to the Inge Morath Photographs and Papers GEN MSS 996
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Inge Morath Photographs and Papers
1858-2012
1953-2002
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Morath, Inge, 1923-2002
GEN MSS 996
1674
372.73 Linear Feet (821 boxes) + 15 broadside, 1 roll, 1 art
232.92 linear feet (743 boxes) + 7 broadsides, 1 roll, 1 computer
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 717-719, 722-723, 840 (audiovisual materials): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 725-732 (electronic files): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Rebecca Miller on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2014, and gift of Rebecca Miller, 2018.
Existence and Location of Copies
The collection consists of the photographic archive and related papers of Inge Morath that document her work as a photographer, chiefly with Magnum Photos, from the early 1950s through her death.
Arrangement
Organized into seven series: I. Photographs, 1896-2001. II. Papers, 1858-2012. III. Photographs and papers from the Morath-Miller home, 1940-2005. IV. Audiovisual Material, 1960-2004. V. Electronic Files, 1994-2005. VI. Artifacts, 1954-2000. VII. December 2018 Acquisition, circa 1970. VIII. April 2018 Acquisition, 1910-2003.
Inge Morath (1923-2002)
Inge Morath was born in Graz, Austria, in 1923. After studying languages in Berlin, she became a translator, then a journalist and the Austrian editor for Heute, an Information Service Branch publication based in Munich. All her life, Morath would remain a prolific diarist and letter-writer. A friend of photographer Ernst Haas, she wrote articles to accompany his photographs and was invited by Robert Capa and Haas to Paris to join the newly founded Magnum agency as an editor and researcher. She began photographing in London in 1951, and joined Magnum Photos as a photographer in 1953. While working on her own first assignments, Morath also assisted Henri Cartier-Bresson during 1953-54, becoming a full member in 1955. In the following years, Morath traveled extensively in Europe, North Africa and the Middle East. Her special interest in the arts found expression in photographic essays published by a number of leading magazines. After her marriage to playwright Arthur Miller in 1962, Morath settled in New York and Connecticut. She first visited the USSR in 1965. In 1972 she studied Mandarin and obtained a visa to China, making the first of many trips to the country in 1978. Much of Morath's most important work consists of portraits, but of passers-by as well as celebrities. She was also adept at photographing places: her pictures of Boris Pasternak's home, Pushkin's library, Chekhov's house, Mao Zedong's bedroom, artists' studios and cemetery memorials are permeated with the spirit of invisible people still present. Inge Morath died in New York City on 30 January 2002. For more detail about Morath's life and career, consult the brief biography compiled by the Inge Morath Foundation in Box 1, Folder 1 of the collection
TypeCollection
https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&1e095da1-51e8-4c77-a2de-c6c9c982ffaf
Associated Materials
Black-and-white 35-millimeter negatives created by Inge Morath are held by Magnum Photos in New York City.
Scope and Contents
Photographic material in the collection includes contact sheets, color slides, and photographic prints.
Morath's documentary photographs depict people and events in a wide range of countries, including Austria, China, England, France, Germany, India, Italy, Romania, Russia, Spain, and Tunisia, as well as throughout Mexico and the United States.
The collection includes portrait studies of public figures, including Yul Brynner, Alexander Calder, Alberto Giacometti, Dustin Hoffman, Henry Moore, Anaïs Nin, Pablo Picasso, Andrei Voznesensky, and Yevgeny Yevtushenko. It also includes projects with her longtime collaborator, artist Saul Steinberg.
Papers in the collection include story lists, captions, notebooks, general files, and publicity related chiefly to her photography. The collection also includes audiovisual material, electronic files, and artifacts.
A group of printed material accompanies the collection and consists of an incomplete set of her monographs, as well as works related to travel, languages, and other subjects.
The collection also chronicles Morath's personal life, including her marriage and family with playwright Arthur Miller, and provides ancillary documentation of his work.
In this guide to the collection, library staff chiefly retained Morath's titles and spellings, while contact sheets include authorized forms of names derived from her story lists.
Chronological arrangements within the collection reflect the image creation date, not the date the photograph was printed. Notes throughout the collection include Morath's "story numbers," when easily discerned by library staff.
Series I, Photographs, includes the bulk of photographic material created by Morath and her personal and family photographs, as well as photographs she collected by other photographers.
Series II, Papers, consists of papers that document the life and work of Morath, including story captions, notebooks, correspondence, clippings, financial records, and awards.
Series III, Photographs and Papers from the Morath-Miller Home, consists of material in the home of Morath and Arthur Miller in Roxbury, Connecticut, immediately before the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library acquired the material in 2014. It includes personal and family photographs, correspondence, writings and travel notebooks, address books, visiting cards, exhibition catalogs, publicity material, art, and ephemera.
Series IV, Audio Visual Material, consists of sound recordings, videocassettes, and films by or about Morath, and includes interviews with her and documentation of her exhibitions.
Series V, Electronic Files, chiefly consists of the electronic files created by Morath, as well as by the Inge Morath Foundation, including image files and backup files, as well as operating system and utility program files used by her.
Series VI, Objects, consists of the items Morath used as a photographer, including a camera, film canisters, and rubber ink stamps used to mark her prints, as well as other personal effects, including scarves and a suitcase.
Photographers -- United States; Women photographers -- United States; Photojournalism; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Photographs; Morath, Inge, 1923-2002; Magnum Photos
- Photographs, 1896-2001; 1; 707430; 136.99 Linear Feet (550 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents the photographic work of Morath, as well as photographic material she collected by other photographers.
  Morath and other Magnum Photos photographers assigned chronological "story numbers" to their projects. These numbers consist of digits for the year of image creation, followed by a sequential number for the story (assignment, job, or project) within the given year, and then often by numbers that identify the roll and exposure frame. Most of the photographic material in the collection have "story numbers" inscribed on their versos, housings, or mounts.
  Related material in Series I, Papers, includes typescript story lists that document the "story numbers" and identify the general subjects, while captions provide group and item-level descriptions of images.
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into five subseries: Contact Sheets, Photographic Prints, Color Transparencies, Personal and Family Photographs, and Collected Photographs.
  - Contact Sheets, 708395
    Organized under four headings: Personal Set, Magnum Photos Paris Set, Duplicate Set, and Reference Print Files.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Associated materials: Information about individual "story numbers" can be found in Series II. Papers, Story Lists subseries.
    This subseries consists of the contact sheets (usually 8 by 10 inches) of 35-millimeter black-and-white negatives created by Morath that represent the bulk of her black-and-white photographic work and document more than 7,700 rolls of film and 240,000 images.
    Associated materials: Information about individual images can be found in Series II. Papers, Captions subseries.
    - Personal Set, 708837
      Arranged sequentially by "story number."
      This material consists of Morath's personal set of contact sheets.
      Many of the contact sheets have inscriptions by Morath on versos, as well as inscriptions on rectos that distinguish individual frames or delineate cropping instructions.
      Some contact sheet "story numbers" may overlap between two or more separate binders.
      - 1953-00. Work with Simon Guttmann (No rolls recorded), 709731 (Box 1)
      - 1953-01. Prêtre ouvrier, workman priest in Paris and Chaville, France (Rolls 1-17), 709730 (Box 2)
        Includes Juliette Gréco, actress
      - 1953-02. Europe, work with Henri Cartier-Bresson (Rolls 19-21 and 23-43, lacking rolls 18, 22), 709729 (Box 2)
        Includes Cartier-Bresson with Pablo Picasso, artist; and Françoise Gilot in Vallauris, France
        Roll 22 probably in the files of Cartier-Bresson
      - 1953-03. Mayfair and Soho in London, England (Rolls 44-69), 709728 (Box 2)
      - 1953-04. Mrs. Eveleigh Nash in London, England (Rolls 70-72), 709727 (Box 2)
      - 1953-05. Hamburg and Friedrichstadt, Germany (Rolls 73-75), 709726 (Box 2)
      - 1953-06. Hjördis Paulina Genberg Tersmeden Niven, wife of David Niven, in London, England (Roll 76), 709725 (Box 2)
      - 1953-07. Robert Fabian, detective at Scotland Yard, London, England (Rolls 77-85), 709724 (Box 2)
      - 1953-08. Burl Ives, actor, writer, and folk music singer, in Ireland (Rolls 86-95), 709723 (Box 2)
        Includes John Huston, film director, screenwriter and actor; and Ives and MacKinlay Kantor, journalist, novelist and screenwriter
      - 1953-09. Cologne Carnival in Cologne, Germany (Rolls 96-97), 709722 (Box 3)
      - 1953-10. Moulin Rouge, film directed by John Huston; includes Zsa Zsa Gabor, actress, and José Ferrer, actor (Rolls 98-103), 709721 (Box 3)
      - 1953-11. London, England, including Soho and Mayfair (Rolls 104-115), 709720 (Box 3)
      - 1953-12. London, England, including Fulton Fish Market and Financial District (Rolls 116-119), 709719 (Box 3)
      - 1953-13. La Fête nationale, also known as Bastille Day, July 14, 1953 (Rolls 120-122), 709718 (Box 3)
      - 1954-01. John Huston, film director, screenwriter and actor, and his wife, Enrica Soma, and children, including Anjelica Huston (Rolls 123-130), 709717 (Box 3)
        Includes Salka Viertel, actress; Peter Viertel, author and screenwriter; and Simone Micheline Bodin, also known as Bettina Graziana; and South Dublin, Ireland
      - 1954-02. Ireland, including Michael Scott, architect, and Louis le Brocquy, painter (Rolls 131-135), 709716 (Box 3)
      - 1954-03. Puck Fair in Killorglin, County Kerry, Ireland (Rolls 136-151), 709715 (Box 4)
      - 1954-04. Louis le Brocquy, painter (Roll 152), 709714 (Box 4)
      - 1954-05. Crufts, dog show at the Olympia exhibition center in London, England (Rolls 153-156), 709713 (Box 4)
      - 1954-06. American girls in Paris, France (Rolls 157-174), 709712 (Box 4)
      - 1954-07. Paul Tortelier, cellist and composer, in London, England (Rolls 175-179), 709711 (Box 4)
      - 1954-08. Henry Moore, sculptor and artist, including his Hoglands farmhouse at Perry Green in Much Hadham, Hertfordshire, England (Rolls 180-181), 709710 (Box 4)
      - 1954-09. Paris, France (Rolls 182-192), 709709 (Box 4)
      - 1954-10. Italy (Rolls 193-200), 709708 (Box 4)
      - 1954-11. Ostia Antica in Rome, Italy (Rolls 201-206), 709707 (Box 4)
      - 1954-12. Archer's Festival, Dammartin-en-Goële, France (Rolls 207-210), 709706 (Box 5)
      - 1954-13. Beast and Beauty fashion contest, Paris, France (Rolls 211-217), 709705 (Box 5)
      - 1954-14. Marquesado de Cerralbo; Louis le Brocquy, painter; and Bacharach am Rhein, Germany (Roll 218), 709704 (Box 5)
      - 1954-15. Gael Elton Mayo, writer and painter, in Madrid, Spain (Roll 219), 709703 (Box 5)
      - 1954-16. Roses in Parc de Bagatelle, Paris, France (Roll 220, two rolls labeled Roll 220), 709702 (Box 5)
      - 1954-17. Reception at Blenheim Palace in Woodstock, Oxfordshire, England, includes Alexandra Mary Spencer-Churchill (Cadogan), Duchess of Marlborough (Rolls 221-224), 709701 (Box 5)
      - 1954-18. Spain (Rolls 225-253), 709700 (Box 5)
        Includes Ignacio Olagüe, paleontologist and historian, and Luis Escobar Kirkpatrick, actor
      - 1954-19. London, England (Rolls 254-258 and 258-262), 709699 (Box 5)
        Includes Barbara Anne Castle, Baroness Castle of Blackburn
      - 1954-20. The Deep Blue Sea, film, screenplay by Terence Rattigan, and directed by Anatole Litvak (Rolls 267-268), 709698 (Box 5)
        Includes Vivien Leigh, actress
      - 1954-21. Ceramics in Madrid, Spain (Roll 269), 709697 (Box 5)
      - 1954-22. Lola Ruiz de Vilató, sister of Pablo Picasso, in Barcelona, Spain (Rolls 270-276), 709696 (Box 5)
        Includes Émile Gilioli, sculptor; and José Ruiz Vilató, also known as J. Fín, a painter and nephew of Pablo Picasso
      - 1954-23. Catalan sculpture at the Museu Nacional d'Art de Catalunya in Barcelona, Spain (Rolls 277-283), 709695 (Box 5)
      - 1954-24. Pamplona in Navarre, Spain (Rolls 318-353, lacking Rolls 284-317), 709694 (Box 6)
        Includes bullfighters Antonio Ordóñez and César Girón
      - 1954-25. Television programs and Arlene Francis, actress, New York (No rolls recorded), 709693 (Box 7)
      - 1955-01. Flood of the Seine, Paris, France (Rolls 355-358), 709692 (Box 9)
      - 1955-02. Alcoholism in Paris, France (Rolls 359-361), 709691 (Box 9)
        Includes images of a barmaid
      - 1955-03. Winter Ball (Bal d'Hiver) in Paris, France (Rolls 362-276), 709690 (Box 9)
        Includes Princess Nina Chavchavadze, born Nina Georgievna of Russia; Charlie Chaplin, actor and filmmaker; and Princess Isabelle, Countess of Paris
      - 1955-04. Funeral for Archduke Eugen of Austria in Innsbruck, Austria, including Zita of Bourbon-Parma, the last Empress of Austria, Queen of Hungary, and Queen of Bohemia (Rolls 377-383), 709689 (Box 9)
      - 1955-05. Austria, carnival in snow (Rolls 384-391), 709688 (Box 9)
      - 1955-06. Home of Paul Cézanne, painter, in Paris, France (Rolls 392-396), 709687 (Box 9)
      - 1955-07. Circus at Velodrome d'Hiver, Paris, France (Rolls 397-398), 709686 (Box 9)
      - 1955-08. Painting by Francisco De Goya in Spain (Roll 399), 709685 (Box 7)
      - 1955-09. La Alberca and Las Hurdes, Spain (Rolls 412-427), 709684 (Box 7)
      - 1955-10. Barcelona, Madrid, and Mallorca, Spain (Rolls 400-411), 709683 (Box 10)
      - 1955-11. Bullfighting in Barcelona, Spain (Rolls 428-435), 709682 (Box 10)
      - 1955-12. Verbena de San Isidro in Madrid, Spain (Rolls 436-441), 709681 (Box 10)
      - 1955-13. Bullfighting, Feria de San Isidro, in Madrid, Spain (Rolls 442-464), 709680 (Box 10)
      - 1955-14. Dominique Aubier, author, Paris, France (Roll 451), 709679 (Box 7)
      - 1955-15. Winefest in Bingen am Rhein, Germany (Roll 452), 709678 (Box 7)
      - 1955-16. Home of Ida Rubinstein, dancer, in Paris, France (Rolls 460, lacking Rolls 453-459, 461), 709677 (Box 7)
      - 1955-17. Bavarian Rococo (Rolls 462 and 464), 709676 (Box 7)
      - 1955-18. Iberian Bronzes (Rolls 465-466), 709675 (Box 7)
      - 1955-19. Ernest "Porter" Tuck, bullfighter known as El Rubio de Boston, in Madrid, Spain (Rolls 467-477), 709674 (Box 10)
      - 1955-20. Wittelsbach Treasure in Munich, Germany (Rolls 478-479), 709673 (Box 7)
      - 1955-21. Peasant wedding in Toledo, Spain (Rolls 480-495), 709672 (Box 10)
      - 1955-22. Bullfighter Luis Miguel Dominguin, Toulouse, France (Rolls 497-499, lacking Roll 498), 709671 (Box 10)
      - 1955-23. Fashion Editor Marie Louise Bousquet, Paris, France (Roll 500), 709670 (Box 10)
      - 1955-24. Dominique Aubier, author, with Robert Delpire, editor, art director, curator, and film producer (Roll 501), 709669 (Box 10)
      - 1955-25. Castile, Spain (Rolls 502-508), 709668 (Box 10)
      - 1955-26. Vigo in Galicia, Spain (Rolls 509-528), 709667 (Box 12)
      - 1955-27. Jules Dassin, film director, Paris, France (Rolls 530-531), 709666 (Box 11)
      - 1955-27. Jules Dassin, film director, Paris, France (Rolls 530-531), 709665 (Box 14)
      - 1955-28. Wedding of Dolores Maria Agatha Wilhelmine Luise, Freiin von Fürstenberg-Hedringen, and Patrick Benjamin Guinness in Paris, France (Rolls 532-534), 709664 (Box 11)
        Includes Princess Dolores von Furstenberg; John Spencer-Churchill, 10th Duke and Duchess of Marlborough, and his wife, Alexandra Mary Spencer-Churchill (Cadogan), Duchess of Marlborough
      - 1955-28. Wedding of Dolores Maria Agatha Wilhelmine Luise, Freiin von Fürstenberg-Hedringen, and Patrick Benjamin Guinness in Paris, France (Rolls 532-534), 709663 (Box 14)
      - 1955-29. Abbé Pierre, Catholic priest (Rolls 535-542), 709662 (Box 11)
      - 1955-29. Abbé Pierre, Catholic priest (Rolls 535-542), 709661 (Box 14)
      - 1955-30. Catalan art in Gerona, Spain (Rolls 543-552), 709660 (Box 11)
      - 1955-30. Catalan art in Gerona, Spain (Rolls 543-552), 709659 (Box 14)
      - 1955-31. Romería de El Rocío in Andalusia, Spain (Rolls 553-584), 709658 (Box 11)
      - 1955-31. Romería de El Rocío in Andalusia, Spain (Rolls 553-584), 709657 (Box 14)
      - 1955-32. Venice, Italy (Rolls 584a-677, lacking Rolls 619, 644, 656, and 660), 709656 (Box 11)
        Includes Mary McCarthy, author, critic and political activist
      - 1955-32. Venice, Italy (Rolls 584a-677, lacking Rolls 619, 644, 656, and 660), 709655 (Box 14)
      - 1955-32. Venice, Italy (Rolls 584a-677, lacking Rolls 619, 644, 656, and 660), 709654 (Box 15)
      - 1955-33. South Africa (Rolls 678-723), 709653 (Box 13)
        Includes Trevor Huddleston, later Archbishop of the Indian Ocean
      - 1955-33. South Africa (Rolls 678-723), 709652 (Box 15)
      - 1955-34. Winston Churchill retirement as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom (Rolls 724-725), 709651 (Box 13)
        Includes Conservative Party politicians Anthony Eden and Duncan Sandys
      - 1955-34. Winston Churchill retirement as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom (Rolls 724-725), 709650 (Box 15)
      - 1955-35. Generation women, including Mercedes Fórmica in Madrid, Spain (Rolls 726-752), 709649 (Box 13)
      - 1955-35. Generation women, including Mercedes Fórmica in Madrid, Spain (Rolls 726-752), 709648 (Box 15)
      - 1955-36. Generation children and London, England (Rolls 753-775), 709647 (Box 16)
      - 1956-01. Gloria Vanderbilt, artist, author, actress, and heiress (Rolls 776-778), 709646 (Box 16)
      - 1956-02. Nancy Berg, actress (Rolls 779-787), 709645 (Box 16)
      - 1956-03. Mary McCarthy, author, critic and political activist (Rolls 788-793), 709644 (Box 16)
        Includes McCarthy's husband, Bowden Broadwater, and brother, actor Kevin McCarthy
      - 1956-04. Loren McIver, artist (Roll 794), 709643 (Box 16)
      - 1956-05. Commander Edward Whitehead for Schweppes in New York (Roll 795), 709642 (Box 16)
      - 1956-06. Metropolitan Opera, New York City (Rolls 796-797), 709641 (Box 16)
      - 1956-07. New York and Boston, Massachusetts (Rolls 798-802), 709640 (Box 16)
      - 1956-08. Christine Arnothy, writer (Rolls 803-805), 709639 (Box 16)
      - 1956-09. Persia (Rolls 806-911), 709638 (Box 16)
        Includes Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Shah of Iran, and his wife, Soraya Esfandiary-Bakhtiari
      - 1956-09. Persia (Rolls 806-911), 709637 (Box 17)
      - 1956-09. Persia (Rolls 806-911), 709636 (Box 18)
      - 1956-09. Persia (Rolls 806-911), 709635 (Box 19)
      - 1956-09. Persia (Rolls 806-911), 709634 (Box 20)
      - 1956-09. Persia (Rolls 806-911), 709633 (Box 21)
      - 1956-10A. Lebanon (Rolls 912-935), 709632 (Box 22)
      - 1956-10A. Lebanon (Rolls 912-935), 709631 (Box 23)
      - 1956-10B. Jordan (Rolls 936-954), 709630 (Box 22)
      - 1956-10B. Jordan (Rolls 936-954), 709629 (Box 23)
      - 1956-10C. Iraq (Rolls 955-961), 709628 (Box 22)
      - 1956-10C. Iraq (Rolls 955-961), 709627 (Box 23)
      - 1956-10D. Syria (Rolls 962-965, lacking Roll 966), 709626 (Box 22)
      - 1956-10D. Syria (Rolls 962-965, lacking Roll 966), 709625 (Box 23)
      - 1956-11. Athina Mary Livanos Onassis with Alexander Onassis and Christina Onassis (Rolls 967-970), 709624 (Box 25)
      - 1956-12. Northern Spain and Aix-en-Provence, France (Rolls 971-984, lacking Roll 984), 709623 (Box 24)
      - 1956-13. Photokina, Cologne (Roll 985), 709622 (Box 25)
      - 1956-14. André Malraux, novelist and art theorist (Roll 986), 709621 (Box 25)
      - 1956-15. Frederick Heyworth Cripps, 3rd Baron Parmoor (Rolls 987-994), 709620 (Box 25)
        Includes George Balanchine, choreographer; and dancers Tanaquil LeClercq and Marjorie Tallchief
      - 1956-16. Capodimonte porcelain (Roll 993A), 709619 (Box 25)
      - 1956-17. New York City Ballet in Paris, France (Roll 994A), 709618 (Box 25)
      - 1956-18. Loren McIver, artist, and Frederick Heyworth Cripps, 3rd Baron Parmoor (Roll 995), 709617 (Box 25)
      - 1956-19. Portugal (Rolls 996-1115, lacking Rolls 1009-1110), 709616 (Box 24)
      - 1956-20. Jean Arp, sculptor, painter, poet and abstract artist, Mont Saint-Michel in Normandy, France (Rolls 1116-1118A), 709615 (Box 24)
      - 1956-21. Dr. Horowitz (Roll 1119), 709614 (Box 25)
      - 1956-22. Lynn Chadwick, sculptor, Paris, France (Rolls 1120-1121), 709613 (Box 25)
      - 1956-23. Barcelona, Spain (Rolls 1122-1123), 709612 (Box 25)
      - 1956-24. Christine Arnothy, writer (Rolls 1124-1125), 709611 (Box 25)
      - 1956-25. Boutiques of Paris, France (Rolls 1126-1128), 709610 (Box 25)
      - 1956-26. Cristóbal Balenciaga, fashion designer, as well as Rue de la Chaise, Paris, France, and Carlos Martínez de Campos, 3rd Duke of la Torre (Roll 1129), 709609 (Box 25)
      - 1957-01. Television animals (Rolls 1130-1155), 709608 (Box 24)
        Includes Linda the Llama in Times Square, New York City
      - 1957-01. Television animals (Rolls 1130-1155), 709607 (Box 25)
      - 1957-01. Television animals (Rolls 1130-1155), 709606 (Box 26)
      - 1957-01A. Parke-Bernet Galleries, New York City (Rolls 2-3), 709605 (Box 24)
      - 1957-01A. Parke-Bernet Galleries, New York City (Rolls 2-3), 709604 (Box 25)
      - 1957-01A. Parke-Bernet Galleries, New York City (Rolls 2-3), 709603 (Box 26)
      - 1957-02. Sarasota, Florida, including the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art (Rolls 1156-1170), 709602 (Box 26)
        Includes Tom Keogh, fashion illustrator, graphic artist, and theatrical designer
      - 1957-02. Sarasota, Florida, including the John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art (Rolls 1156-1170), 709601 (Box 27)
      - 1957-03. Father Pierre? Duval, workman priest in France (Rolls 1171-1175), 709600 (Box 26)
      - 1957-03. Father Pierre? Duval, workman priest in France (Rolls 1171-1175), 709599 (Box 27)
      - 1957-04. British Museum, London, England (Rolls 1178-1186, lacking Rolls 1176-1177, 1184-1185, and 1187-1189), 709598 (Box 26)
        Includes photographs for work, Claude Roy, Arts Sauvages (Paris: R. Delpire, 1957)
        Rolls for the British Museum not extant
      - 1957-04. British Museum, London, England (Rolls 1178-1186, lacking Rolls 1176-1177, 1184-1185, and 1187-1189), 709597 (Box 27)
      - 1957-05. Theodora Keogh, novelist, in Paris, France (Rolls 1190-1191 lacking Rolls 1187-1189), 709596 (Box 26)